blogger-hints-and-tips.blogspot.in 2014-06-30

# Privacy Policy | Blogger-Hints-and-Tips

**This article describes the personal information that Blogger-Hints-and-Tips collects, and how it is used.**  

**Introduction:**

All web servers, including the ones that host [Blogger-Hints-and-Tips](http://blogger-hints-and-tips.blogspot.com/), store some information about visitors, including (at least) IP address, browser and its configuration, the date and time of the visit and and details about how the visitor reached the site (from a referring page, or using what search-keywords).

This data is tracked for administration and maintenance purposes, and lets me know what articles readers are interested in. It is also used for administration and site-maintenance, and for promoting the site to potential advertisers. A key point is that it cannot personally identify visitors to this site, so is not considered as personal information.

Users who leave comments are required to be logged in, and may therefore leave personally identifying information.   The only information that is collected or stored by [Blogger-Hints-and-Tips](http://blogger-hints-and-tips.blogspot.com/) is the login account that is provided by the comment-er, and this is used only to respond to the comment(s) that are left.

**Cookies and Web Beacons**

This site may use cookies to store data about visitor's preferences and history in order to provide better service and to present him/her with customized content.

Advertising partners, like [Adsense](http://blogger-hints-and-tips.blogspot.com/2010/02/setting-up-adsense-on-your-blog.html) and [Chitika](http://blogger-hints-and-tips.blogspot.com/2010/02/chitika-overview.html) and affiliates like [Amazon](http://blogger-hints-and-tips.blogspot.com/2011/09/blogger-amazon-integration-is-finished.html), may also use cookies, scripts and/or web beacons to track visitors, so they can display relevant advertisements and other useful information. Such tracking is done directly by the advertisers with their own servers and is controlled by their own privacy policies.

You can disable cookies in your browser settings if you have privacy concerns. It is not recommended to do this for all sites is not recommended, because it may cause problems with the way you prefer to use some sites. Instead, it's better to disable or enable cookies on a per-site basis. See your web-browser(s) documentation for information about blocking cookies and other tracking mechanisms.

**Google Inc would like you to be aware that:**

Advertisements served by Google, Inc., and affiliated companies may be controlled using cookies. These let Google display ads based on your visits to this site and others that use Google advertising services. Learn how to opt out of Google's cookie usage. Tracking done by Google is subject to Google's privacy policies.

The DoubleClick DART cookie is used by Google in ads on publisher websites displaying AdSense-for-content advertising. When users visit an AdSense publisher’s website and view or click an ad, a cookie may be put on the user’s browser. Data from these cookies is used to help AdSense better serve and manage the ads on this site and others. You can opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the [Google ad and content network privacy policy.](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html)

**For more information:**

Queries about this policy should be sent to:  bloggerhintsandtips@gmail.com 

**HTML link code:**

**BB (forum) link code:**
